72. Look away from the light. Smartphones have changed the way we live. We use them
for just about everything now, communicating, learning, laughing, and even getting around
our cities. But not all the changes have been good ones. One negative consequence of our
smartphone use is that it's wreaking havoc on our body's natural cycles. The problem
has to do with the blue light given off by smartphones and other electronics. Blue light
has a very short wavelength and produces a higher amount of energy than normal light.
Smartphone producers favor it because it matches the brightness of sunlight. This makes it
easier to read what's on your smartphone's screen in daylight. But it's this very
similarity to sunlight that causes our body's problems. The human body normally releases
a chemical called melatonin after the sun goes down. This chemical tells us it's time
to go to sleep. But here's where your smartphone comes in. Imagine a normal evening of riding
the bus home, cooking dinner, and then going to bed. You're probably checking your smartphone
the whole time, right? Well, all that blue light is tricking your body into thinking
that it's still daytime. As a result, your natural cycle is disturbed and it's harder
to get a good night's sleep. A disturbed sleep cycle has been proven to lead to other
health problems. In one study, researchers linked working a night shift to increase
chances of diabetes and heart disease. Luckily, we're not totally powerless. There are some
things we can do to beat blue light. Try to avoid using your smartphone for an hour or
two before bed. There are also special glasses you can buy to block out blue light. And you
could always just stop using your smartphone altogether. Good luck with that one.